《冰雪奇缘》
∮ 冰天雪地风儿吹 ∮
∮ Born of cold and winter air ∮
∮ 山中雨水凝起 ∮
∮ And mountain rain combining ∮
∮ 冰雪的威力美又邪 ∮
∮ This icy force both foul and fair ∮
∮ 晶莹的心值得采集 ∮
∮ Has a frozen heart worth mining ∮
∮ 坚冰凿开 ∮
∮ So out through the heart ∮
∮ 清又冽 ∮
∮ Cold and clear ∮
∮ 勇敢爱不怕未来 ∮
∮ Strike for love and strike for fear ∮
∮ 美丽清晰在眼前 ∮
∮ See the beauty sharp and sheer ∮
∮ 劈开冰儿哟 ∮
∮ Split the ice apart ∮
∮ 叩开冻结的心 嘿 ∮
∮ And break the frozen heart Hup, ho ∮
∮ 小心点 开始吧 ∮
∮ Watch your step Let it go ∮
∮ 嘿 哟 ∮
∮ Hup, ho ∮
∮ 小心点 开始吧 ∮
∮ Watch your step Let it go ∮
∮ 美丽 霸气 ∮
∮ Beautiful Powerful ∮
∮ 危险 冻人 ∮
∮ Dangerous Cold ∮
∮ 冰霜的魔力神秘绝伦 ∮
∮ Ice has a magic Can't be controlled ∮
∮ 一人抵不过 ∮
∮ Stronger than one ∮
∮ 十人抵不过 ∮
∮ Stronger than ten ∮
∮ 一百人也得摇头叹！∮
∮ Stronger than a hundred men! ∮
∮ 哦！∮
∮ Oh! ∮
∮ 冰天雪地风儿吹 ∮
∮ Born of cold And winter air ∮
∮ 山中雨水凝起 ∮
∮ And mountain rain combining ∮
∮ 冰雪的威力美又邪 ∮
∮ This icy force both foul and fair ∮
∮ 晶莹的心值得采集 ∮
∮ Has a frozen heart worth mining ∮
∮ 坚冰凿开 ∮
∮ Cut through the heart ∮
∮ 清又冽 ∮
∮ Cold and clear ∮
∮ 勇敢爱不怕未来 ∮
∮ Strike for love and strike for fear ∮
∮ 美丽与危机都存在 ∮
∮ There's beauty and there's danger here ∮
∮ 劈开冰儿哟 ∮
∮ Split the ice apart ∮
∮ 小心冻结的心 ∮
∮ Beware the frozen heart ∮
快跟上 斯文
Come on, Sven.
埃尔莎 嘘！
Elsa. Psst!
埃尔莎！
Elsa!
快起来 快起来 快起来！
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
安娜 回去睡觉
Anna, go back to sleep.
我睡不着
I just can't.
天亮了 我也醒了
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
我们得玩游戏
So, we have to play.
跟自己玩去
Go play by yourself.
你想堆个雪人吗？
Do you want to build a snowman?
来嘛 来嘛 来嘛！
Come on, come on, come on!
快用魔法！
Do the magic!
快用魔法嘛！
哦…
Oh…
- 准备好了吗？- 嗯哼
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
太赞了！
This is amazing!
看好了！
Watch this!
嗨 我是雪宝
Hi, I'm Olaf,
我喜欢暖暖的拥抱
and I like warm hugs.
我爱你 雪宝！
I love you, Olaf!
雪宝…
Olaf…
好痒！
Tickle bumps!
噢！
Oh!
加油！
Hang on!
接住我！
Catch me!
好嘞！
Gotcha!
再来一次！
Again!
等等！
Wait!
- 噢嚯！- 慢点儿！
- Whoo-hoo! - Slow down!
哇哦！
Whoo!
安娜！
Anna!
妈妈！爸爸！
Mama! Papa!
不 不…
No, no…
没事了 安娜 我接住你了
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
埃尔莎 你都干了些什么？
Elsa, what have you done?
你的能力失控了
This is getting out of hand.
这只是个意外 对不起 安娜！
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
- 天啊 她身体冷冰冰的 - 我知道该去哪儿了
- Oh. She's ice cold. - I know where we have to go.
是冰？
Ice?
快点 斯文
Faster, Sven.
斯文！
Sven!
请帮帮忙！我女儿出事了
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
是国王来了
It's the king.
- 石精？- 嘘！
- Trolls? - Shush!
我正在偷听呢
I'm trying to listen.
真可爱 我就留下你们好啦
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
陛下
Your Majesty.
这魔力是天生的 还是受了诅咒？
Born with the powers, or cursed?
天生的 而且越来越强了
Born. And they're getting stronger.
过来 过来
Here, here.
很幸运 被击中的不是心脏
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
心脏的转变难以扭转
The heart is not so easily changed.
但脑袋或许可以改变
But the head can be persuaded.
做你觉得该做的
Do what you must.
为确保安全 我建议移除
I recommend we remove all magic.
所有与魔法有关的东西 甚至记忆
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
但不用担心 我会把开心留下
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
她会没事的
She will be okay.
但她会忘记我有魔法？
But she won't remember I have powers?
这样才是最好的
It's for the best.
听我说 埃尔莎 你的魔力只会与日俱增
Listen to me, Elsa. Your power will only grow.
它很美丽…
There is beauty in it…
但也很危险
but also great danger.
你必须学着控制它
You must learn to control it.
恐惧将与你为敌
Fear will be your enemy.
不！
No!
我们会保护她
We'll protect her.
她一定能学会控制的
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
在那之前…
Until then…
我们将锁起大门
we'll lock the gates.
裁减侍卫
We'll reduce the staff.
我们将限制她和别人接触
We will limit her contact with people,
不让任何人知道她的魔力
and keep her powers hidden from everyone.
包括安娜
Including Anna.
啊
Ah.
埃尔莎？
Elsa?
∮ 你想不想堆个雪人？∮
∮ Do you wanna build a snowman? ∮
∮ 来吧 我们去玩耍 ∮
∮ Come on, let's go and play ∮
∮ 我再没见过你出来 ∮
∮ I never see you anymore ∮
∮ 门快打开 ∮
∮ Come out the door ∮
∮ 我怕你真的会离开 ∮
∮ It's like you've gone away ∮
∮ 我们曾是好姐妹 现在却不理不睬 ∮
∮ We used to be best buddies and now we're not ∮
∮ 多希望你能讲明白 ∮
∮ I wish you would tell me why ∮
∮ 你想不想堆个雪人？∮
∮ Do you wanna build a snowman? ∮
∮ 想玩什么都可以呀 ∮
∮ It doesn't have to be a snowman ∮
快走开 安娜
Go away, Anna.
∮ 好啦 拜 ∮
∮ Okay, bye ∮
手套能帮你忙
The gloves will help.
瞧？藏起来了
See? Conceal it.
不去感受
Don't feel it.
不让它显露
Don't let it show.
∮ 你想不想堆个雪人？∮
∮ Do you wanna build a snowman? ∮
∮ 或是骑车兜个风？∮
∮ Or ride our bike around the halls? ∮
∮ 真的好想有人陪我 ∮
∮ I think some company is overdue ∮
∮ 只能朝画像说话让我好难过 ∮
∮ I've started talking to the pictures on the walls ∮
坚持住 贞德
Hang in there, Joan.
∮ 空空荡荡的房间 好寂寞 ∮
∮ It gets a little lonely all these empty rooms ∮
∮ 只有钟摆滴答走 ∮
∮ Just watching the hours tick by ∮
我好害怕
I'm scared.
它越来越强了！
It's getting stronger!
沮丧只会让它变得更糟 平静下来
Getting upset only makes it worse. Calm down.
不！别碰我！
No! Don't touch me!
求你了 我不想伤害你们
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
两星期后见！
See you in two weeks!
你们非得走吗？
Do you have to go?
你会没事的 埃尔莎
You'll be fine, Elsa.
皇后殿下
Your Highness.
埃尔莎？
Elsa?
∮ 拜托 我知道你在 ∮
∮ Please I know you're in there ∮
∮ 别人都纷纷问起你 ∮
∮ People are asking where you've been ∮
∮ 我在努力变得更勇敢 ∮
∮ They say "Have courage" And I'm trying to ∮
∮ 给你力量与陪伴 ∮
∮ I'm right out here for you ∮
∮ 把门打开 ∮
∮ Just let me in ∮
∮ 我们只剩下彼此 欢笑不再 ∮
∮ We only have each other It's just you and me ∮
∮ 怎么面对未来？∮
∮ What are we gonna do? ∮
你想不想堆个雪人？
Do you wanna build a snowman?
（三年后）
全体上岸！
All ashore!
欢迎来到艾伦戴尔！
Welcome to Arendelle!
注意脚下安全
Watch your step, please.
大门很快就会打开
The gates will be opening soon.
我为啥要穿这个呀？
Why do I have to wear this?
因为女王成年了
Because the queen has come of age.
今天是加冕日！
It's Coronation Day!
这又不关我的事
That's not my fault.
你想要什么 斯文？
What do you want, Sven?
「给我点零食」
"Give me a snack."
得说什么来着？
What's the magic word?
「请」
"Please."
诶！不对 要分享
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
简直不敢相信 她们终于把门打开了！
I can't believe they're finally opening up the gates!
- 而且是一整天！- 快点 珀西！
- And for a whole day! - Faster, Percy!
艾伦戴尔 我们那神秘的交易伙伴
Arendelle, our most mysterious trade partner.
敞开大门 让我来
Open those gates so I may unlock.
挖出你的秘密 榨干你的财富
your secrets and exploit your riches.
我是不是说出来了？
Did I say that out loud?
哦！我等不及想见见
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait.
女王和公主的容貌
to see the queen and the princess.
我敢说一定非常可爱
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
要我说肯定美极了
I bet they are beautiful.
安娜公主？
Princess Anna?
- 安娜公主？- 呃？什么？
- Princess Anna? - Huh? Yeah?
抱歉吵醒你 殿下
Oh. Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
不 不 不 你没吵醒我
No, no, no, you didn't.
我早就起来了
I've been up for hours.
谁啊？
Who is it?
还是我 殿下
Still me, ma'am.
大门即将打开 该梳洗准备了
The gates will open soon. Time to get ready.
好的
Of course.
准备什么？
Ready for what?
您姐姐的加冕日 殿下
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
我姐姐的加冕日
My sister's corneration.
是加冕日！
It's Coronation Day!
今天是加冕日！
∮ 打开窗子！∮
∮ The window is open! ∮
∮ 推开门！∮
∮ So's that door! ∮
∮ 我从不知道他们会这么做 ∮
∮ I didn't know they did that anymore ∮
∮ 连沙拉盘子都有八千个！∮
∮ Who knew we owned 8, 000 salad plates? ∮
∮ 无人的走廊常走过 ∮
∮ For years I've roamed these empty halls ∮
∮ 闲置的舞厅好寂寞 ∮
∮ Why have a ballroom with no balls? ∮
∮ 今日大门终将会敞开！∮
∮ Finally they're opening up the gates! ∮
∮ 人群拥挤 触手可及 ∮
∮ There'll be actual, real, live people ∮
∮ 好像有点不适应 ∮
∮ It'll be totally strange ∮
∮ 可我早已准备迎接新世界！∮
∮ But wow! Am I so ready for this change! ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 拥抱歌声 ∮
∮ There'll be music ∮
∮ 拥抱光 ∮
∮ There'll be light ∮
∮ 我第一次 ∮
∮ For the first time ∮
∮ 在生命里 ∮
∮ In forever ∮
∮ 彻夜舞蹈至天明 ∮
∮ I'll be dancing through the night ∮
∮ 我大概有点得意忘形 ∮
∮ Don't know if I'm elated or gassy ∮
∮ 欢声笑语不停息 ∮
∮ But I'm somewhere in that zone ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 我不会孤寂 ∮
∮ I won't be alone ∮
∮ 我等不及想见所有人！∮
∮ I can't wait to meet everyone! ∮
∮ 要是遇见了「那个他」呢？∮
∮ What if I meet The One? ∮
∮ 我将会穿上新晚装 ∮
∮ Tonight imagine me gown and all ∮
∮ 靠着墙迷人又闪亮 ∮
∮ Fetchingly draped against the wall ∮
∮ 好一副精致端庄的模样 ∮
∮ The picture of sophisticated grace ∮
∮ 他突然出现在前方 ∮
∮ I suddenly see him standing there ∮
∮ 陌生脸庞俊俏 ∮
∮ A beautiful stranger ∮
∮ 身材高大健壮 ∮
∮ Tall and fair ∮
∮ 我想把巧克力塞得嘴鼓囊囊！∮
∮ I wanna stuff some chocolate in my face! ∮
∮ 我们整晚聊个不停 ∮
∮ But then we laugh and talk all evening ∮
∮ 有一点不可思议 ∮
∮ Which is totally bizarre ∮
∮ 这一切终于不再是我的想象 ∮
∮ Nothing like the life I've led so far ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ For the first time in forever ∮
∮ 拥抱惊喜与欢笑 ∮
∮ There'll be magic there'll be fun ∮
∮ 我第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ For the first time in forever ∮
∮ 得到关注的目光 ∮
∮ I could be noticed by someone ∮
∮ 我知道这样有一些疯狂 ∮
∮ And I know it is totally crazy ∮
∮ 想象浪漫相遇 ∮
∮ To dream I'd find romance ∮
∮ 但第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ But for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 我至少有机会 ∮
∮ At least I've got a chance! ∮
∮ 不要进来 ∮
∮ Don't let them in ∮
∮ 别被看见 ∮
∮ Don't let them see ∮
∮ 做个好女孩 ∮
∮ Be the good girl ∮
∮ 像从前一样 ∮
∮ You always have to be ∮
∮ 隐藏 ∮
∮ Conceal ∮
∮ 别去想 ∮
∮ Don't feel ∮
∮ 表演开场 ∮
∮ Put on a show ∮
∮ 一步踏错 ∮
∮ Make one wrong move ∮
∮ 所有人会知晓 ∮
∮ And everyone will know ∮
∮ 但一切就在今天 ∮
∮ But it's only for today ∮
∮ 一切就在今天 ∮
∮ It's only for today ∮
∮ 我不能继续等待 ∮
∮ It's agony to wait ∮
∮ 让守卫把这扇门 ∮
∮ Tell the guards to open up ∮
∮ 打开 ∮
∮ The gate ∮
∮ 我第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ For the first time in forever ∮
∮ 不要进来 别被看见 ∮
∮ Don't let them in Don't let them see ∮
∮ 我的梦如愿以偿 ∮
∮ I'm getting what I'm dreaming of ∮
∮ 做个好女孩 ∮
∮ Be the good girl ∮
∮ 像从前一样 ∮
∮ You always have to be ∮
∮ 改变的契机 ∮
∮ A chance to change ∮
∮ 不再孤寂 ∮
∮ My lonely world ∮
∮ 隐藏 ∮
∮ Conceal ∮
∮ 真爱的寻觅 ∮
∮ A chance to find true love ∮
∮ 隐藏 别想 别被发现 ∮
∮ Conceal, don't feel Don't let them know ∮
∮ 我知道明天都会消失 ∮
∮ I know it all ends tomorrow ∮
∮ 必须今天开始！∮
∮ So it has to be today! ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 第一次 ∮
∮ For the first time ∮
∮ 在生命里 ∮
∮ In forever ∮
∮ 不再有禁锢！∮
∮ Nothing's in my way! ∮
嘿！
Hey!
太对不起了 你没受伤吧？
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
嘿
Hey.
呃… 没 没 我很好
Uh… No, no, I'm okay.
你确定？
Are you sure?
嗯 我只是没在看路
Yeah. I just wasn't looking where I was going.
但我很好 棒极了
But I'm great, actually.
哦… 谢天谢地
Oh… Thank goodness.
哦！呃…
Oh! Uh…
我是南艾尔的汉斯王子
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
我是艾伦戴尔的安娜公主
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
「公主」？日安
"Princess"? My Lady.
哦！
Oh!
- 哇哦 - 哇哦 哇哦…
- Whoa. - Whoa, whoa, whoa…
- 呃… - 呼
- Um… - Whew.
嗨 第二遍了
Hi. Again.
哦 死小子！
Oh, boy!
这有点糟糕
This is awkward.
不是说「你笨手笨脚」 只是我们…
Not "You're awkward, " but just because we're…
我笨手笨脚 你超厉害的 等等 啥？
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous. Wait, what?
我想为我的马冲撞到
I'd like to formally apologize.
艾伦戴尔的公主 以及随后发生的事情
for hitting the princess of Arendelle with my horse.
正式向你道歉
And for every moment after.
没事！真的没事
No! No, no. It's fine.
我不是那种公主
I'm not that princess.
我是说 要是你撞到了我姐姐埃尔莎
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
那可就… 不好办了！
it would be… Yeesh!
因为 你懂的…
Because, you know…
你好啊
Hello.
不过 算你走运
But, lucky you,
只是我而已
it's just me.
「只是」你？
"Just" you?
钟声响了 加冕仪式要开始了
The bells. The coronation.
我得走了
I better go.
我真的该走了 真的 呃…
I have to go. I better go. Uh…
再见！
Bye!
哦 不要啊！
Oh, no. Oh!
女王陛下 请摘下您的手套
Your Majesty, the gloves.
艾伦戴尔女王埃尔莎
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
艾伦戴尔女王埃尔莎！
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
有请艾伦戴尔女王埃尔莎
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
有请艾伦戴尔公主安娜
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
哦 这里吗？你确定？
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
因为我觉得我不应该…
Because I don't think I'm supposed to…
哦 好吧
Oh. Okay.
嗨
Hi.
跟我说「嗨」吗？哦…
"Hi" me? Oh…
呃… 嗨
Um… Hi.
你真漂亮
You look beautiful.
谢谢 你也「满」漂亮
Thank you. You look beautiful-ler.
呃 不是「满」 你看起来才不胖
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
是比我更美
But more beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以…
So…
派对就是这样的
This is what a party looks like.
比我想象的要暖和点
It's warmer than I thought.
什么味道这么好闻？
What is that amazing smell?
是巧克力
Chocolate.
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
- 这是黄鼠狼镇公爵 - 是「威尔镇」！
- The Duke of Weaseltown. - "Weselton"!
女王陛下 我是威尔镇公爵
Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
作为贵国最紧密的贸易伙伴 由我邀请您跳加冕以来的
As your closest partner in trade it seems only fitting.
第一支舞
that I offer you.
应该是再合适不过了
your first dance as queen.
一 二 跳
One-two, and jump.
呃…
Uh…
谢谢您 不过 我不跳舞
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
哦…
Oh…
不过我妹妹会跳舞
But my sister does.
- 什么？- 哦！你真幸运
- What? - Oh! Lucky you.
哦 我不…
Oh, I don't think…
要是你要晕倒了就告诉我 我会拉住你的
If you swoon, let me know. I'll catch you.
抱歉
Sorry.
像孔雀一样轻盈
Like an agile peacock.
哦！哦
Ow! Ow.
说真的 打开城堡的大门真是太好了
Speaking of, so great to have the gates open.
他们之前为什么要关上门啊？
Why did they shut them in the first place?
你知道是怎么回事吗？嗯？
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
- 不知道 - 不知道
- No. - No.
好吧 等等！
All right. Hang on!
他们可不是无缘无故就叫我「小北斗星」的！
They don't call me the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
哦哈！
Oh-ho!
像猴子一样灵巧 我可要飞起来了
Like a chicken with the face of a monkey, I fly.
小姐 准备好再来一次的时候
Let me know when you're ready.
一定要告诉我啊
for another round, Milady.
他真的很有活力
Well, he was sprightly.
特别是他还穿着高跟鞋
Especially for a man in heels.
你感觉还好吗？
Are you okay?
从没比现在更好过 这样太棒了
I've never been better. This is so nice.
真希望可以一直这样下去
I wish it could be like this all the time.
我也是
Me, too.
但是不行
But it can't.
- 为什么？- 就是不行
- Why not? - It just can't.
我失陪一下
Excuse me for a minute.
我感到非常荣幸
I'd be honored.
真高兴我拉住你了
Glad I caught you.
是你 汉斯
Hans.
哦
Oop.
通常情况下我可以在整个大厅里滑来滑去！
I often had a whole parlor to myself to slide!
- 哦！- 啊！
- Oh! - Oops!
对不起
Sorry.
我敢说 你的长相也很不错了
Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
啊
Ah.
你的头发是怎么回事？
What's this?
哦 我生来就是这样
Uh, I was born with it.
虽然在梦里 我被石精亲过
Although, I dreamed I was kissed by a troll.
我喜欢你的头发
I like it.
是啊 就是这样
Yeah, the whole thing.
你明白了吧
You got it.
好了 等下 等下 你有多少个兄弟？
Okay, wait, wait. So, you have how many brothers?
我有十二个哥哥
Twelve older brothers.
其中的三个一直当我不存在
Three of them pretended I was invisible,
真的 差不多有两年都是这样
literally, for two years.
太可怕了
That's horrible.
哥哥们就是这样
It's what brothers do.
姐姐们也是啊
And sisters.
埃尔莎和我小时候亲密无间
Elsa and I were really close when we were little.
后来 有一天 她就开始不理我
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
我从来都不知道为什么
and I never knew why.
我永远不会把你拒之门外的
I would never shut you out.
好吧 我能说点疯狂的话吗？
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
我就喜欢疯狂一点
I love crazy.
∮ 我的生活一直不能尽如人意 ∮
∮ All my life has been A series of doors in my face ∮
∮ 直到今天邂逅了你 ∮
∮ And then suddenly I bump into you ∮
我也是这么想的 因为…
I was thinking the same thing, because, like…
∮ 我一直都在寻找 ∮
∮ I've been searching my whole life ∮
∮ 属于自己的位置 ∮
∮ To find my own place ∮
∮ 可能是派对让人疯狂 ∮
∮ And maybe it's the party talking ∮
∮ 或许是巧克力太过甜蜜 ∮
∮ Or the chocolate fondue ∮
∮ 但是和你在一起 ∮
∮ But with you ∮
∮ 和你在一起 我找到了归处 ∮
∮ But with you I found my place ∮
∮ 我的眼中只有你 ∮
∮ I see your face ∮
∮ 这种感觉 美妙新奇 ∮
∮ And it's nothing like I've ever known before ∮
∮ 爱情之门 ∮
∮ Love is an open ∮
∮ 终于敞开！∮
∮ Door! ∮
∮ 爱情之门 ∮
∮ Love is an open ∮
- ∮ 终于敞开 ∮ - ∮ 终于敞开∮
- ∮ Door ∮ - ∮ Door ∮
∮ 爱情之门 终于敞开 ∮
∮ Love is an open door ∮
- ∮ 你和在一起 ∮ - ∮ 和你在一起 ∮
- ∮ With you ∮ - ∮ With you ∮
∮ 爱情之门 终于敞开 ∮
∮ Love is an open door ∮
- ∮ 我觉得这太疯狂了 ∮ - ∮ 怎么了？∮
- ∮ I mean, it's crazy ∮ - ∮ What? ∮
- ∮ 我们吃掉了对方的 ∮ - ∮ 三明治 ∮
- ∮ We finish each other's ∮ - ∮ Sandwiches ∮
∮ 我就是想说这个！∮
∮ That's what I was gonna say! ∮
∮ 从未遇到过 ∮
∮ I've never met someone ∮
∮ 和我如此相似的人 ∮
∮ Who thinks so much like me ∮
- ∮ 拉钩！∮ - ∮ 再来一次！∮
- ∮ Jinx! ∮ - ∮ Jinx again! ∮
∮ 我们心有灵犀 只有一种解释 ∮
∮ Our mental synchronization Can have but one explanation ∮
- ∮ 你 ∮ - ∮ 和我 ∮
- ∮ You ∮ - ∮ And I ∮
- ∮ 命中 ∮ - ∮ 注定 ∮
- ∮ Were ∮ - ∮ Just ∮
∮ 应该在一起 ∮
∮ Meant to be ∮
- ∮ 告别 ∮ - ∮ 告别 ∮
- ∮ Say goodbye ∮ - ∮ Say goodbye ∮
∮ 过去的悲伤 ∮
∮ To the pain of the past ∮
∮ 我们再也无需悲伤 ∮
∮ We don't have to feel it anymore ∮
∮ 爱情之门已经敞开 ∮
∮ Love is an open door ∮
∮ 爱情之门 已经 ∮
∮ Love is an open ∮
- ∮ 敞开 ∮ - ∮ 敞开 ∮
- ∮ Door ∮ - ∮ Door ∮
∮ 生命有无限可能 ∮
∮ Life can be so much more ∮
- ∮ 和你在一起 ∮ - ∮ 和你在一起 ∮
- ∮ With you ∮ - ∮ With you ∮
∮ 爱情之门 已经 ∮
∮ Love is an open ∮
- ∮ 敞开 ∮ - ∮ 敞开 ∮
- ∮ Door ∮ - ∮ Door ∮
我能说句疯狂的话吗？
Can I say something crazy?
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
我可以更疯狂吗？
Can I say something even crazier?
我愿意！
Yes!
- 请让一下 - 不好意思 哦…
- Coming through. - Excuse me. Oh…
- 不好意思 借过 - 哦！
- Pardon. Sorry. - Oh!
请让一下好吗？
Can we just get around you there?
谢谢 哦！她在那
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
埃尔莎！
Elsa!
哦 我是说 皇后 还是我 呃…
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um…
请允许我向您介绍南艾尔的汉斯王子
May I present Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
我们希望…
We would like…
呃 您能祝福我们的…
Uh, your blessing…
婚姻
of our marriage.
- 婚姻？- 是！
- Marriage? - Yes!
不好意思 我没太明白
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
其实 我们也没太明白呢
Well, we haven't worked out all the details ourselves.
我们得花几天计划一下婚礼
We'll need a few days to plan the ceremony.
不过宴会上肯定会有浓汤 牛排和冰激凌 而且…
Of course, we'll have soup, roast and ice cream. And then…
对了 你可以住在这里吗？
Wait. Would we live here?
- 这里？- 当然可以！
- Here? - Absolutely!
- 安娜！- 哦！
- Anna! - Oh!
我们可以邀请你的十二个哥哥都来和我们一起
We can invite all 12 of your brothers to stay with us.
什么？不 不 不
What? No, no, no.
- 我们这里当然住得下 - 等下 慢点说
- Of course we have the room. - Wait, slow down.
他的哥哥们不能住在这里
No one's brothers are staying here.
你们也不能结婚
No one is getting married.
你说什么？
Wait, what?
我能跟你单独谈谈吗？
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
不用 你要说什么都可以和我们俩说
No. Whatever you have to say, you can say to both of us.
好吧 你不能嫁给一个刚刚认识的男人
Fine. You can't marry a man you just met.
如果是真爱就没问题
You can if it's true love.
安娜 你知道什么是真爱吗？
Anna, what do you know about true love?
知道的比你多
More than you.
你只知道怎么拒人于千里外
All you know is how to shut people out.
你想让我祝福你们 但是我不会这么做
You asked for my blessing, but my answer is no.
我先走了
Now, excuse me.
女王陛下 如果我能…
Your Majesty, if I may ease your…
不 不行 而且我认为你该走了
No, you may not. And I think you should go.
派对结束了 关上城门
The party is over. Close the gates.
- 是 陛下 - 什么？
- Yes, Your Majesty. - What?
埃尔莎 别这样 等一下
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
把手套还给我！
Give me my glove!
埃尔莎 求你了 求求你
Elsa, please, please.
我不能再过这样的日子了！
I can't live like this anymore!
那就离开这里
Then leave.
我对你做了什么？
What did I ever do to you?
别说了 安娜
Enough, Anna.
不 我要说 为什么？你为什么不理我了？
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
你为什么把整个世界都拒之门外？
Why do you shut the world out?
你到底在害怕什么？
What are you so afraid of?
我让你别说了！
I said, enough!
魔法
Sorcery.
我就知道这里很可疑
I knew there was something dubious going on here.
埃尔莎
Elsa.
她来了！
There she is!
对！就是她！
Yes! It is her!
埃尔莎女王
Queen Elsa.
我们美丽的女王！
Our beautiful queen!
女王陛下？您还好吗？
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
不
No.
她在那！拦住她！
There she is! Stop her!
拜托了 请离我远一点 离我远点
Please, just stay away from me. Stay away.
怪物 怪物！
Monster. Monster!
埃尔莎！
Elsa!
等等！
Wait, please!
埃尔莎 停下！
Elsa, stop!
小心 安娜！
Anna!
不
No.
你看这个海峡
The fjord.
- 下雪了！- 下雪了？
- Snow! - Snow?
是啊 下雪了
Yes, snow.
- 你还好吗？- 不好
- Are you all right? - No.
这件事你知道吗？
Did you know?
不知道
No.
看啊 下雪了 下雪了！
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
女王诅咒了整片大陆！
The queen has cursed this land!
得有人去阻止她！你快去追她！
She must be stopped! You have to go after her.
等等 不行！
Wait, no!
是你！你也会魔法吗？
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
你也是怪物吗？
Are you a monster, too?
不 不 我就是个普通人
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
是啊 我可以保证
That's right, she is.
是好的那种普通
In the best way.
而且我姐姐也不是什么怪物
And my sister is not a monster.
她差点杀死我！
She nearly killed me!
- 你在冰上滑倒了而已 - 那也是她弄出来的冰
- You slipped on ice. - Her ice.
这是个意外 她被吓到了
It was an accident. She was scared.
她不是故意的 真的
She didn't mean it. She didn't mean any of this.
今晚是我的错 我不该逼她
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
所以我应该
So, I'm the one.
- 去把她找回来 - 什么？
- that needs to go after her. - What?
- 把我的马牵来 谢谢 - 安娜 不行
- Bring me my horse, please. - Anna, no.
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
埃尔莎才不危险
Elsa is not dangerous.
我会带她回来 我会处理好一切的
I'll bring her back, and I'll make this right.
我和你一起去
I'm coming with you.
不 我需要你帮我管理艾伦戴尔
No, I need you here to take care of Arendelle.
我深感荣幸
On my honor.
我授予汉斯王子管理艾伦戴尔的权利
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
你确定可以信任她？
Are you sure you can trust her?
我不想你受伤
I don't want you getting hurt.
她是我姐姐
She's my sister.
她永远不会伤害我的
She would never hurt me.
∮ 今夜的山上 白雪闪亮 ∮
∮ The snow glows white On the mountain tonight ∮
∮ 渺无人烟的地方 ∮
∮ Not a footprint to be seen ∮
∮ 孤独的国土 ∮
∮ A kingdom of isolation ∮
∮ 而我是这里的女王 ∮
∮ And it looks like I'm the queen ∮
∮ 狂风正在呼啸 ∮
∮ The wind is howling ∮
∮ 犹如内心风暴 ∮
∮ Like this swirling storm inside ∮
∮ 已经无力隐瞒 上天知我苦心 ∮
∮ Couldn't keep it in Heaven knows I tried ∮
∮ 不要进来 别被看见 ∮
∮ Don't let them in Don't let them see ∮
∮ 做个好女孩 像以前一样 ∮
∮ Be the good girl You always have to be ∮
∮ 隐藏 别想 别被发现 ∮
∮ Conceal, don't feel Don't let them know ∮
∮ 他们却已知晓 ∮
∮ Well, now they know ∮
∮ 随它吧！随它吧！∮
∮ Let it go! Let it go! ∮
∮ 如今不必再隐藏 ∮
∮ Can't hold me back anymore ∮
∮ 随它吧！随它吧！∮
∮ Let it go! Let it go! ∮
∮ 关上门 转身离开 ∮
∮ Turn away and slam the door ∮
∮ 我不在乎 ∮
∮ I don't care ∮
∮ 别人说的话 ∮
∮ What they're going to say ∮
∮ 任狂风呼啸 ∮
∮ Let the storm rage on ∮
∮ 严寒再不能令我害怕 ∮
∮ The cold never bothered me anyway ∮
∮ 从前遥不可及 如今触手可得 ∮
∮ It's funny how some distance Makes everything seem small ∮
∮ 过去的恐惧 ∮
∮ And the fears that once controlled me ∮
∮ 再也不会烦扰我 ∮
∮ Can't get to me at all ∮
∮ 大展身手的时候已经来到 ∮
∮ It's time to see what I can do ∮
∮ 打破极限 尽情创造 ∮
∮ To test the limits and break through ∮
∮ 没有对错 ∮
∮ No right, no wrong ∮
∮ 没有规则 ∮
∮ No rules for me ∮
∮ 我自由了！∮
∮ I'm free! ∮
∮ 随它吧！∮
∮ Let it go! ∮
∮ 我可以迎风飞扬 ∮
∮ I am one with the wind and sky ∮
∮ 随它吧！随它吧！∮
∮ Let it go! Let it go! ∮
∮ 再不会见我哭泣 ∮
∮ You'll never see me cry ∮
∮ 这里是 ∮
∮ Here I stand ∮
∮ 我的归宿 ∮
∮ And here I'll stay ∮
∮ 任狂风呼啸 ∮
∮ Let the storm rage on ∮
∮ 我的雪花 冲向云霄 ∮
∮ My power flurries through the air ∮
∮ 布满大地 ∮
∮ Into the ground ∮
∮ 我的灵魂 盘旋涌动 映入万千雪花 ∮
∮ My soul is spiraling in frozen fractals all around ∮
∮ 心绪所致 冰晶绽放 宛若晶莹冰花 ∮
∮ And one thought crystallizes Like an icy blast ∮
∮ 我再也不会回头 ∮
∮ I'm never going back ∮
∮ 过往已无可留恋 ∮
∮ The past is in the past ∮
∮ 挣开吧！那锁链！∮
∮ Let it go! Let it go! ∮
∮ 我要升华如黎明曙光 ∮
∮ And I'll rise like the break of dawn ∮
∮ 随它吧！随它吧！∮
∮ Let it go! Let it go! ∮
∮ 那完美的女孩已经不再 ∮
∮ That perfect girl is gone ∮
∮ 这是全新的我 ∮
∮ Here I stand ∮
∮ 在朝阳之中 ∮
∮ In the light of day ∮
∮ 任狂风呼啸！∮
∮ Let the storm rage on! ∮
∮ 严寒再不能令我害怕 ∮
∮ The cold never bothered me anyway ∮
埃尔莎！
Elsa!
埃尔莎！是我啊 安娜
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
我不想让你把夏天冻成冬天的
your sister who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer.
对不起 都是我的错
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
当然啦 她要是早告诉我她的秘密
Of course, none of it would have happened.
也不至于这样
if she had just told me her secret.
她好烦啊
She's a stinker.
哇！
Whoa!
哦 不 别别别！回来啊！
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
不 不要啊！
No, no, no!
算了
Okay.
雪 就非得是雪
Snow. It had to be snow.
她就不能使热点的魔法嘛
She couldn't have had tropical magic.
给峡湾盖上白沙还有 暖洋洋的…
that covered the fjords in white sand and warm…
火！
Fire!
冷 冷 冷 冷
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
流浪橡树交易站
Wandering Oaken's Trading Post.
哇 还有桑拿！
Ooh."And sauna"!
- 哟呼 - 嗯？
- Yoo-hoo. - Hmm?
夏季清仓大甩卖
Big summer blowout.
泳装 木屐半价出售
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
还有我自制的防晒霜 如何？
and a sun balm of my own invention, yah?
哦 好极了 先给我来双靴子吧？
Oh. Great. For now, um, how about boots?
冬装和靴子？
Winter boots and dresses?
那在我们的冬季专柜
That would be in our winter department.
哦 嗯…
Oh. Um…
好奇的问一下
I was just wondering.
有没有其他年轻女子…
Has another young woman…
比如说女王啦 我也说不好
the queen perhaps, I don't know,
经过这里？
passed through here?
大雪天还头脑发热跑出来的
The only one crazy enough to be out in this storm.
只有你哦 小妹妹
is you, dear.
你和这位小哥
You and this fellow.
哟呼
Yoo-hoo.
夏季清仓大甩卖
Big summer blowout.
胡萝卜
Carrots.
嗯？
Huh?
你挡住了
Behind you.
哦！是啊 对不起
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
外面真的是七月飘雪 是不是啊？
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
雪是从哪里来的？
Wherever could it be coming from?
从北峰
The North Mountain.
北峰
North Mountain.
总共40块
That will be 40.
40块？太贵 10块
Forty? No, 10.
哦 小哥 不行啊
Oh, dear, that's no good.
这是我们冬季的藏货
See, this is from our winter stock,
现在供给和需求是很成问题的
where supply and demand have a big problem.
你真要跟我扯供需关系？
You want to talk about a supply and demand problem?
我靠卖冰吃饭的
I sell ice for a living.
哦 那生意现在可不好做
Ooh. That's a rough business to be in right now.
我是说 真是…
I mean, that is really…
真是太不幸了
That's unfortunate.
40块 不二价
Still 40.
不过赠送免费橡木桑拿一次
But I will throw in a visit to Oaken's sauna.
哟呼 嗨 亲们
Yoo-hoo. Hi, family.
哟呼！
Yoo-hoo!
我只有10块 帮帮忙
Ten is all I got. Help me out.
好吧 10块只够买这个 别的不行了
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
我就问你一个问题
Okay, just tell me one thing.
北峰上出什么事了？
What was happening on the North Mountain?
是不是像施了法术？
Did it seem magical?
没错！
Yes!
你现在给我站开点 我先搞定这个奸商
Now, back up while I deal with this crook, here.
你叫人家什么？
What did you call me?
好啦 行啦 我出去了
Okay, okay. I'm out.
哇！
Whoa!
拜拜
Bye-bye.
没有 斯文 我没有买到胡萝卜
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
但是我找到休息的地方
But I did find us a place to sleep.
还免费哦
And it's free.
对不起 下手重了点
I'm sorry about this violence.
再送你一品脱碱鱼
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
大家还是好朋友
so we have good feelings.
只要外套和靴子 还有吗？
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
嗯…
Uh…
∮ 驯鹿比人友善 ∮
∮ Reindeers are better than people ∮
∮ 斯文 你是不是也这样看？∮
∮ Sven, don't you think that's true? ∮
∮ 「没错 人会打你 骂你 还会骗你」 ∮
∮ "Yeah, people will beat you And curse you and cheat you" ∮
∮ 「他们都是坏蛋 除了你」 ∮
∮ "Every one of them's bad, except you"∮
∮ 哇 谢谢啦 哥们 ∮
∮ Aw. Thanks, buddy. ∮
∮ 但没有驯鹿的气味 ∮
∮ But people smell better than reindeers ∮
∮ 斯文 是不是这样？∮
∮ Sven, don't you think I'm right? ∮
∮ 「你又对了 他们都没气味 但你有」 ∮
∮ "That's once again true For all, except you" ∮
∮ 说得好 真是精彩的一晚 ∮
∮ You got me Let's call it a night ∮
∮ 「晚安」 ∮
∮ "Good night" ∮
∮ 小心别被 ∮
∮ Don't let the frostbite ∮
∮ 冻伤 ∮
∮ Bite ∮
合唱真动听
Nice duet.
是你啊 你要干嘛？
It's just you. What do you want?
我想让你载我上北峰
I want you to take me up the North Mountain.
我不拉人
I don't take people places.
我再说一遍
Let me rephrase that.
嘿
Hey.
带我上北峰
Take me up the North Mountain.
麻烦你
Please.
听着 我知道怎么让这寒冷天气结束
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
明早出发
We leave at dawn.
你忘了买斯文的胡萝卜了
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
哦 不好意思
Oops, sorry.
对不起 抱歉 我不是…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't…
我们现在就走 立刻马上
We leave now. Right now.
驾！
Whew!
抓牢了！我们喜欢开块
Hang on! We like to go fast.
- 我喜欢快 - 哇！哇 哇…
- I like fast. - Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa…
把脚放下 这刚上过漆的
Get your feet down. This is fresh lacquer.
老实说 你不是乡下长大的？
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
恶！
Ugh!
- 才不是 我在城堡里长大的 - 嗯
- No, I was raised in a castle. - Hmm.
那跟我说说
So, uh, tell me,
女王怎么了 为什么乱下雪？
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
哦 嗯…
Oh. Well…
都是我的错
It was all my fault.
我定了婚 她就抓狂了
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
因为我才那天刚认识那个人
because I'd only just met him, you know, that day.
然后她说她不会祝福我们的婚姻 然后…
And she said she wouldn't bless the marriage, and…
等等 你和刚认识的人订婚了？
Wait. You got engaged to someone you just met that day?
是啦 反正就是我生气了 她也生气了
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
然后她就想走开
and then she tried to walk away,
我就抓住她的手套…
and I grabbed her glove…
等等！
Hang on!
你说你跟个那天
You mean to tell me you got engaged.
刚认识的人订婚了？
to someone you just met that day?
嘿 你专心点听好吗
Yes. Pay attention.
但是说起来 她老是带着手套
But the thing is, she wore the gloves all the time,
所以我想 她可能是有洁癖
so I just thought, maybe she has a thing about dirt.
你父母没告诉你要小心陌生人吗？
Didn't your parents ever warn you about strangers?
是啊 他们说过
Yes, they did.
但汉斯王子不是陌生人
But Hans is not a stranger.
哦 真的？他姓什么？
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
「来自南艾尔」
"Of the Southern Isles."
- 他最爱吃什么？- 三明治
- What's his favorite food? - Sandwiches.
- 最好的朋友叫什么？- 好像叫约翰
- Best friend's name? - Probably John.
- 眼睛什么颜色？- 梦幻色
- Eye color? - Dreamy.
- 脚多大？- 脚多大根本不重要
- Foot size? - Foot size doesn't matter.
你跟他吃过饭没有？
Have you had a meal with him yet?
要是你讨厌他的吃相怎么办？
What if you hate the way he eats?
如果他挖鼻孔的样子讨人嫌怎么办？
What if you hate the way he picks his nose?
挖鼻孔？
Picks his nose?
还吃掉
And eats it.
不好意思 人家是王子
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
- 男人都一样 - 恶
- All men do it. - Ew.
听着 那不重要 我们是真爱
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
听起来不像真爱
It doesn't sound like true love.
你还是什么爱情专家啊？
Are you some sort of love expert?
不是 但我有朋友是
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
你还有朋友
You have friends.
是爱情专家？我不信
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
- 别说话 - 不要 不要
- Stop talking. - No, no, no. No, no.
- 我倒想见见这些… - 我说真的 安静
- I'd like to meet these… - No, I mean it.
斯文 跑
Sven, go.
快跑！
Go!
- 那是什么？- 狼
- What are they? - Wolves.
狼？
Wolves?
- 我们怎么办？- 我来处理
- What do we do? - I got this.
你… 别掉下去 也别被狼给吃了
You just… Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
我想帮忙！
But I want to help!
- 不用 - 为什么不用？
- No. - Why not?
因为我不相信你的判断
Because I don't trust your judgment.
说什么？
Excuse me?
谁会和刚认识的男人结婚？
Who marries a man she just met?
那是真爱！
It's true love!
哇！
Whoa!
哇 哇！
Whoa. Whoa!
克里斯豆腐！
Christopher!
我叫「克里斯多夫」！
It's "Kristoff"!
哇
Ow!
低头！
Duck!
你差点烧着我！
You almost set me on fire!
但没有烧着
But I didn't.
准备跳 斯文！
Get ready to jump, Sven!
你不要指挥他
You don't tell him what to do.
- 嘿！- 我来！
- Hey! - I do!
跳 斯文！
Jump, Sven!
好险！
Phew!
我刚买的雪橇
But I just paid it off.
哦 别 别
Uh-oh. No. No.
不要啊
No!
啊啊！天啊 天啊！
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
抓住！
Grab on!
往上拉 斯文 拉！
Pull, Sven. Pull!
哇
Whoa.
我会赔你雪橇的 还有上面的东西
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
如果你不想帮我了 我也能理解
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
我当然是不想再帮她了
Of course I don't want to help her anymore. In fact,
实际上 出了这种事 我再也不想帮别人了
this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
是往这里吗？
It's this way?
「她自己一个人会挂掉的」
"She'll die on her own."
- 我不介意 - 我就往这儿啦
- I can live with that. - Here we go.
「她要是死了 雪橇就没人赔了」
"But you won't get your new sled if she's dead."
我觉得 应该是往上
I think, actually, it's up.
有时候 我真的不喜欢你
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
等等！我们来了
Hold up! We're coming.
你要来？
You are?
我是说 好吧 我允许让你跟着
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
艾伦戴尔
Arendelle.
完全被雪覆盖了
It's completely frozen.
没事的 埃尔莎会把雪化掉的
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
会吗？
Will she?
是啦 现在赶路
Yeah. Now, come on.
往北峰走这边？
This way to the North Mountain?
应该是这边
More like this way.
我从来没发现 冬天的景色这么美
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
是啊
Yeah.
真的是很漂亮
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
但是白茫茫的一片
But it's so white.
多点色彩会不会更美？
You know, how about a little color?
我觉得加点深红色 嫩绿色不错
I'm thinking maybe some crimson, chartreuse.
黄色怎么样？
How about yellow?
不对 不能加黄色 黄色和白色？
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
根本不搭
No go.
你们说是不是？
Am I right?
- 你好 - 你好吓人
- Hi. - You're creepy.
- 哇！- 拿走啦
- Whoa! - I don't want it.
- 你拿着 - 别把我的头弄掉了
- Back at you. - Please don't drop me.
- 不要 - 别扔了 就是个头而已嘛
- No. - Come on, it's just a head.
好吧 初次见面不太顺利
All right. We got off to a bad start.
啊呀 不要 身体跑过来了！
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
等等 我现在看到的是什么？
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
为什么你们都跟蝙蝠一样大头朝下？
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
好吧 你等下
All right, wait one second.
噢 嗯…
Oh. Uh…
噢！
Oh!
- 谢谢 - 不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
我完整啦
Now, I'm perfect.
嗯 还缺一点
Well, almost.
刚刚就像我整个人生都颠倒了
It was like my whole life got turned upside down.
哦！对不起太用力了！
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
- 头好晕！- 我不小心… 你没事吧？
- Head rush! - I was just… Are you okay?
岂止没有事？简直棒极了！
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
我一直想要个鼻子
I've always wanted a nose.
好可爱
So cute.
好可爱 就像独角兽宝宝的角
It's like a little baby unicorn.
但是…嘿！哇！
But… Hey! Whoa!
哦
Oh.
这样更好看啦
I love it even more.
好吧 让我们重新认识一次
All right, let's start this thing over.
嗨 大家好
Hi, everyone.
我叫雪宝
I'm Olaf.
我喜欢暖暖的拥抱
And I like warm hugs.
雪宝？
Olaf?
没错 就是雪宝
That's right. Olaf.
你叫？
And you are?
哦 嗯…
Oh. Um…
我叫安娜
I'm Anna.
那边长得很奇怪的驴子叫什么？
And who's the funky-looking donkey over there?
- 它叫斯文 - 哦哦
- That's Sven. - Uh-huh.
那麋鹿叫什么？
And who's the reindeer?
斯文
Sven.
哦 嗯 好吧 这样就简单了
Oh, the… Oh. Okay. That makes things easier for me.
哇 看呐 他还想亲我
Aw, look at him trying to kiss my nose.
- 伦家也喜欢你 - 雪宝
- I like you, too. - Olaf.
- 是埃尔莎创造了你吗？- 是啊 问这干嘛？
- Did Elsa build you? - Yeah. Why?
你知道她在哪吗？
Do you know where she is?
- 真不错 - 知道 怎么了？
- Fascinating. - Yeah. Why?
你能带我们去找她吗？
Do you think you could show us the way?
能 怎么了？
Yeah. Why?
这是怎么回事？啊！
How does this work? Ow!
别乱动 斯文 好好听着
Stop it, Sven. I'm trying to focus, here.
- 怎么了？- 我来告诉你怎么了
- Yeah. Why? - I'll tell you why.
我们要让埃尔莎把夏天变回来
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
- 夏天？- 没错
- Summer? - Mmm-hmm.
哦 不知道为什么
Oh. I don't know why,
我总是对夏天心驰神往
but I've always loved the idea of summer.
大太阳 火力四射
And sun, and all things hot.
是吗？
Really?
但我以为你没经历过热天气呢
I'm guessing you don't have much experience with heat.
确实没
Nope.
但有时候 我喜欢闭上眼睛
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
想象着自己置身于盛夏
and imagine what it would be like when summer does come.
∮ 蜜蜂飞舞 孩子们吹着蒲公英 ∮
∮ Bees will buzz. Kids will blow dandelion fuzz. ∮
∮ 而我也在过着夏天 ∮
∮ And I'll be doing whatever snow does in summer. ∮
∮ 手拿冷饮 ∮
∮ A drink in my hand. ∮
∮ 躺在沙滩上晒太阳 ∮
∮ My snow up against the burning sand. ∮
∮ 也许会晒成性感的古铜色 ∮
∮ Probably getting gorgeously tanned ∮
∮ 在夏天 ∮
∮ in summer. ∮
∮ 我终于要见到 ∮
∮ I'll finally see a summer breeze ∮
∮ 夏日的风吹散冬日的烦恼 ∮
∮ blow away a winter storm. ∮
∮ 气温渐渐变暖 ∮
∮ And find out what happens to solid water ∮
∮ 小河水也都解冻了 ∮
∮ when it gets warm. ∮
∮ 我迫不及待地 ∮
∮ And I can't wait to see ∮
∮ 想看到小伙伴们的反应 ∮
∮ what my buddies all think of me. ∮
∮ 想象一下我会变得多么灿烂 ∮
∮ Just imagine how much cooler I'll be ∮
∮ 在夏天！∮
∮ in summer! ∮
∮ 炽热和冷冽 多么强烈∮
∮ The hot and the cold are both so intense. ∮
∮ 交织在一起 多么般配 ∮
∮ Put them together. It just makes sense. ∮
∮ 冬天是休养生息的好时节 ∮
∮ Winter's a good time to stay in and cuddle. ∮
∮ 但如果到了夏天 我会变成一个… ∮
∮ But put me in summer and I'll be a… ∮
∮ 快乐的雪人！∮
∮ happy snowman! ∮
∮ 即使生活不容易 ∮
∮ When life gets rough ∮
∮ 我也会坚持自己的梦想 ∮
∮ I like to hold on to my dream. ∮
∮ 悠闲晒着夏日暖阳 烦恼全抛光 ∮
∮ Relaxing in the summer sun Just letting off steam. ∮
∮ 哦 天空 ∮
∮ Oh, the sky ∮
∮ 是那么蓝 ∮
∮ will be blue. ∮
∮ 你们也会和我在一起 ∮
∮ And you guys will be there, too. ∮
∮ 我会像其他雪人一样 ∮
∮ When I finally do ∮
∮ 好好享受 在夏天！∮
∮ what frozen things do in summer! ∮
- 我得告诉他 - 别那样
- I'm gonna tell him. - Don't you dare.
∮ 在夏天！∮
∮ In summer! ∮
我们走吧！埃尔莎在那边
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
我们把夏天找回来吧！
Let's go bring back summer!
我来啦！
I'm coming!
总得有人告诉他
Somebody's gotta tell him.
不 你把树皮朝下放了
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
树皮应该朝上
The bark needs to be face-up.
- 朝下更容易干 - 朝上！
- Bark down is drier. - Bark up!
- 朝下！- 爸爸！
- Bark down! - Papa!
斗篷？有人需要斗篷吗？
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
艾伦戴尔人民感激您 阁下
Arendelle is indebted to you, Your Highness.
城堡开放了
The castle is open.
城堡的大厅会供应汤和热饮
There is soup and hot glogg in the great hall.
给你 发给大家
Here, pass these out.
汉斯王子！
Prince Hans!
难道我们只能坐在这里一边受冻
Are we expected to just sit here and freeze.
一边看着你把艾伦戴尔的出口物资都发给大家？
while you give away all of Arendelle's tradable goods?
这是安娜公主的命令
Princess Anna has given her orders.
我正想说这事！
And that's another thing!
你难道不明白吗？你的公主有可能
Has it dawned on you that your princess may be conspiring.
被那个巫师迷惑了
with a wicked Sorceress.
想把我们都害死
to destroy us all?
不准你质疑公主
Do not question the princess.
她让我负责艾伦戴尔
She left me in charge.
若是有人叛国
and I will not hesitate.
我会毫不手软的
to protect Arendelle from treason.
叛国？
Treason?
哇！哇！
Whoa! Whoa!
哇 别激动
Whoa, boy. Easy.
别激动
Easy.
这是安娜公主的马
It's Princess Anna's horse.
那公主在哪里？
So, where is the princess?
- 她会在哪里？- 她在哪？
- Where could she be? - Where is she?
安娜公主遇到麻烦了
Princess Anna is in trouble.
有人愿意和我一起去找她吗？
I need volunteers to go with me to find her.
- 我去 - 我也愿意去
- I'll go. - I volunteer.
我派两个人跟你去 阁下
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
时刻提高警惕
Be prepared for anything.
如果遇到了女王
And should you encounter the queen,
你们就要让冬天结束
you are to put an end to this winter.
- 明白了吗？- 嗯
- Do you understand? - Hmm.
你打算怎么让这样的天气结束？
So, how exactly are you planning to stop this weather?
哦 我打算和我姐姐聊聊
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
这就是你的计划？
That's your plan?
我的卖冰生意就指望你和你姐聊聊了？
My ice business is riding on you talking to your sister?
没错
Yep.
那看来你一点也不怕她？
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
- 我为什么要怕她？- 嗯
- Why would I be? - Yeah.
我猜她肯定是最漂亮 最温柔的女人
I bet she's the nicest, gentlest, warmest person ever.
哦 快看啊
Oh. Look at that.
我被刺穿了
I've been impaled.
现在怎么办？
What now?
嗯…
Mmm…
太陡峭了
It's too steep.
我只有一根绳子 而你又不会爬山
I've only got one rope and you don't know how to climb mountains.
谁说的？
Says who?
嗯？
Hmm?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我要去见我姐姐
I'm going to see my sister.
你真是不要命
You're gonna kill yourself.
别踩那里
I wouldn't put my foot there.
- 别让我分心 - 也别踩那里
- You're distracting me. - Or there.
你怎么知道埃尔莎愿意见你？
How do you know Elsa even wants to see you?
好了 我不和你聊了
All right. I'm just blocking you out.
我得专心爬山
because I gotta concentrate, here.
知道吗 躲在山里的人
You know, most people who disappear.
都是想要一个人静一静的
into the mountains want to be alone.
没人喜欢孤独
Nobody wants to be alone.
也许除了你
Except maybe you.
我不孤独 我有朋友的 好不好？
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
你是说那些爱情专家？
You mean, the love experts?
是的 那些爱情专家
Yes, the love experts.
啊…
Ah…
我是不是快到了？
Please tell me I'm almost there.
上边的空气是不是有点稀薄？
Does the air seem a bit thin to you up here?
等一下
Hang on.
嘿 斯文？
Hey, Sven?
我不知道能不能解决问题
Not sure if this is gonna solve the problem,
但我发现了一个楼梯
but I found a staircase that leads exactly.
正好通往你们要去的地方
where you wanted to go.
哈哈！太好了 接住我！
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
谢了 这是个信任大考验
Thanks. That was like a crazy trust exercise.
哇
Whoa.
这才是冰雪的世界
Now, that's ice.
我真想哭
I might cry.
哭吧 我不会笑话你的
Go ahead. I won't judge.
好了 别担心 过来
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
我扶着你
I got you.
好了 你留在这里吧 伙计
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
完美无瑕
Flawless.
敲门啊
Knock.
快敲啊
Just knock.
她为什么不敲啊？
Why isn't she knocking?
难道她不会敲门吗？
Do you think she knows how to knock?
哈 门没锁
Huh. It opened.
很不错
That's a first.
哦 你们在这里等我吧
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
- 什么？- 上一次我把男人介绍给她
- What? - The last time I introduced her to a guy,
她把一切都冻住了
she froze everything.
但是… 哦 别这样！
But, but… oh, come on!
这里是冰雪宫殿 我的毕生所爱！
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
回见 斯文
Bye, Sven.
你也等在这里 雪宝
You, too, Olaf.
- 我？- 让我们单独谈一下
- Me? - Just give us a minute.
好吧
Okay.
一 二
One, two,
- 三… - 四…
- three… - Four…
哇
Whoa.
埃尔莎？
Elsa?
是我 安娜
It's me, Anna.
安娜
Anna.
哇 埃尔莎 你变得不一样了
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
变漂亮了
It's a good different.
这地方…
And this place…
太美了
it's amazing.
谢谢
Thank you.
我一直都不了解自己的能力
I never knew what I was capable of.
那些事情太抱歉了 如果我知道…
I'm so sorry about what happened. If I'd have known…
别说了 没关系的
No, no, no. It's okay.
你不用道歉 但你最好还是走吧
You don't have to apologize, but you should probably go.
求你了
Please.
我才到这里啊
But I just got here.
你应该在艾伦戴尔的
You belong down in Arendelle.
你也是
So do you.
不 安娜 我应该在这里
No, Anna, I belong here.
独自一人
Alone.
这样我就不会伤害到别人了
Where I can be who I am without hurting anybody.
说到这个…
Actually, about that…
- 六十！- 等一下 什么声音？
- Sixty! - Wait. What is that?
嗨！我叫雪宝 最喜欢暖暖的拥抱！
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
雪宝？
Olaf?
嗯 是你创造了我
Yeah. You built me.
记得吗？
Remember that?
你活过来了？
And you're alive?
嗯… 我想是的
Um… I think so.
他和我们儿时堆的雪人一样
He's just like the one we built as kids.
嗯
Yeah.
埃尔莎 以前我们那么要好
Elsa, we were so close.
以后我们也可以那样
We can be like that again.
- 接住我！- 慢点儿！
- Catch me! - Slow down!
安娜！
Anna!
不
No.
我们不能 再见了 安娜
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
埃尔莎 等等
Elsa, wait.
别过来 我只是想保护你
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
你不必保护我 我不害怕
You don't have to protect me. I'm not afraid.
别又不理我了
Please don't shut me out again.
∮ 请别关上门 ∮
∮ Please don't slam the door ∮
∮ 你不必再保持距离 ∮
∮ You don't have to keep your distance anymore ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 我终于懂得 ∮
∮ I finally understand ∮
∮ 第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ For the first time in forever ∮
∮ 我们携手解决问题 ∮
∮ We can fix this hand in hand ∮
我们可以一起下山
We can head down this mountain together.
∮ 你不必活在恐惧中 ∮
∮ You don't have to live in fear ∮
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 我会陪着你 ∮
∮ I will be right here ∮
安娜
Anna.
∮ 你快回家 ∮
∮ Please go back home ∮
∮ 过美好人生 ∮
∮ Your life awaits ∮
∮ 享受阳光 享受自由 ∮
∮ Go enjoy the sun And open up the gates ∮
- 对 但… - 我知道
- Yeah, but… - I know.
∮ 你是好意 但请离开 ∮
∮ You mean well But leave me be ∮
∮ 没错 我是一个人 ∮
∮ Yes, I'm alone ∮
∮ 但我很自由 ∮
∮ But I'm alone and free ∮
∮ 离开我 你会更安全 ∮
∮ Just stay away And you'll be safe from me ∮
∮ 事实并非如此 ∮
∮ Actually, we're not ∮
∮ 这话什么意思？∮
∮ What do you mean, you're not? ∮
∮ 我想你好像不知道 ∮
∮ I get the feeling you don't know ∮
∮ 不知道什么？∮
∮ What do I not know? ∮
∮ 艾伦戴尔陷入了寒冷的 ∮
∮ Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep ∮
∮ 严冬 ∮
∮ Deep snow ∮
什么？
What?
似乎你把所有地方都变成了寒冬
You kind of set off an eternal winter everywhere.
所有地方？
Everywhere?
没关系 你可以让它们化冻
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
不行 我不知道怎么做
No, I can't. I don't know how.
我知道你能做到
Sure you can. I know you can.
∮ 因为第一次在生命里 ∮
∮ 'Cause for the first time in forever ∮
∮ 哦 我真笨！不能随心所欲！∮
∮ Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free! ∮
∮ 你不必害怕 ∮
∮ You don't have to be afraid ∮
∮ 逃不开内心的风暴 ∮
∮ No escape from the storm inside of me ∮
∮ 我们能携手渡难关 ∮
∮ We can work this out together ∮
∮ 我控制不了力量！∮
∮ I can't control the curse! ∮
∮ 我们能停止这风暴 ∮
∮ We'll reverse the storm you've made ∮
∮ 安娜别说了 只会更糟糕！∮
∮ Anna, please you'll only make it worse! ∮
- ∮ 别害怕 ∮ - ∮ 我太害怕！∮
- ∮ Don't panic ∮ - ∮ There's so much fear! ∮
∮ 我们能让阳光普照 ∮
∮ We'll make the sun shine bright ∮
∮ 你在这里不安全！∮
∮ You're not safe here! ∮
∮ 我们可以共同面对 ∮
∮ We can face this thing together ∮
∮ 不！∮
∮ No! ∮
∮ 我们可以赶走寒冬 ∮
∮ We can change this winter weather ∮
∮ 一切都会好起来 ∮
∮ And everything will be all right ∮
∮ 我做不到！∮
∮ I can't! ∮
安娜！
Anna!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我没事
I'm okay.
没事
I'm fine.
这是谁？
Who's this?
等等 这不重要 就…
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just…
你得离开
You have to go.
不 我知道我们能解决这问题
No, I know we can figure this out together.
怎么解决？
How?
你有什么力量赶走这寒冬？
What power do you have to stop this winter?
阻止我？
To stop me?
安娜 我想我们得走了
Anna, I think we should go.
不 不能留下你 埃尔莎
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
不 你走吧
Yes, you are.
住手！放我们下来！
Stop! Put us down!
快走
Go away.
注意！
Heads up!
小心我的屁股！
Watch out for my butt!
把人丢来丢去真不礼貌！
It is not nice to throw people!
等等 等等 别激动 放松点
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants. Okay, relax.
- 冷静！冷静一些！- 好！好吧！
- Just calm down! Calm down! - Okay! All right!
- 我没事 - 别去惹大雪人
- I'm okay. - Just let the snowman be.
- 我很冷静 - 很好
- I'm calm. - Great.
噢！拜托！
Oh! Come on!
看到了吧？你把它惹毛了
Oh. Look, see? Now, you made him mad.
我来引开他 你们快跑
I'll distract him. You guys go.
不 不！没说你们！
No, no! Not you guys!
现在这样根本跑不了
This just got a whole lot harder.
小心！
Look out!
跑！快跑！
Run! Run!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我打中他了！
I got him!
哇！停下！
Whoa! Stop!
这有一百英尺高
It's a 100-foot drop.
是两百
It's 200.
哇！
Ow!
- 你要干嘛？- 我要挖一个雪锚
- What's that for? - I'm digging a snow anchor.
好吧 要是掉下去了怎么办？
Okay. What if we fall?
下面有20英尺厚的积雪
There's 20 feet of fresh powder down there.
掉下去也就是像掉在枕头上一样
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
希望如此
Hopefully.
好了 安娜 我数到三
Okay, Anna. On three.
- 好的 - 一…
- Okay. - One…
告诉我什么时候跳 我准备好了
You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
- 二… - 我都准备好了！好！
- Two… - I was born ready! Yes!
冷静
Calm down.
树！
Tree!
这是怎… 哇哦！
What the… Whoa!
怎么回事
That happened.
天啊 我都走形了
Man, am I out of shape.
好了 嘿 安娜！
There we go. Hey, Anna!
斯文！你们在哪儿？
Sven! Where did you guys go?
我们完全甩掉那个大棉花糖啦
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
嘿！我们正说你呢
Hey! We were just talking about you.
一切都好 一切都好
All good things, all good things.
不！
No!
这也没什么区别啦 不是吗？
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
雪宝！
Olaf!
坚持住 伙计们！
Hang in there, guys!
快 再快点！
Go. Go faster!
- 等等 什么？- 嘿！
- Wait, what? - Hey!
喔！
Ow!
克里斯多夫！
Kristoff!
别再回来！
Don't come back!
不会的
We won't.
嘿 你说得对 就像摔在枕头上
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
雪宝！
Olaf!
没知觉了！我的腿没知觉了！
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
- 那是我的腿 - 哦！
- Those are my legs. - Ooh!
嘿 帮我个忙 抓住我的屁股
Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
哦 这下好多了
Oh. That feels better.
嘿 斯文！他找到我们了
Hey, Sven! He found us.
谁是我的亲亲小驯鹿啊？
Who's my cute little reindeer?
别跟他用那种口气说话
Don't talk to him like that.
你挠我痒痒
You're tickling me.
我帮你
Here.
喔哦！
Whoa!
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 你的头怎么样了？- 啊！哦！
- How's your head? - Ah! Ooh!
还好 呃…
It's fine. Uh…
呃 我没事 我头盖骨厚着呢
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
我没有头盖骨
I don't have a skull.
也没有骨头
Or bones.
那么 呃… 现在怎么办？
So, uh… So, now what?
现在怎么办？
Now what?
怎么办？
哦…
Oh…
我该怎么办？
what am I gonna do?
她把我扔出来了
She threw me out.
这样子的天气我还不能回艾伦戴尔
I can't go back to Arendelle with the weather like this.
还有你的卖冰生意
And then there's your ice business.
嘿 嘿 别担心我的生意
Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
- 先担心一下你的头发！- 什么？
- Worry about your hair! - What?
我刚刚从悬崖上掉下来 你应该看看你的头发
I just fell off a cliff. You should see your hair.
不是 你的头发变白了
No, yours is turning white.
白了？这… 是怎么回事？
White? It's… What?
因为她打中了你 不是吗？
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
看起来很丑吗？
Does it look bad?
- 不会 - 你犹豫了
- No. - You hesitated.
不 我没犹豫
No, I didn't.
安娜 你需要帮助 知道吗？过来
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
好吧！我们要去哪儿？
Okay! Where are we going?
去见我的朋友们
To see my friends.
那群爱情专家？
The love experts?
- 爱情专家？- 嗯哼
- Love experts? - Uh-huh.
别担心 他们会搞定这事儿的
And don't worry, they'll be able to fix this.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为我以前看他们做过
Because I've seen them do it before.
我觉得自己也是个爱情专家
I like to consider myself a love expert.
打起精神
Get it together.
控制力量
Control it.
别去想 别去想
Don't feel. Don't feel.
别去想
Don't feel.
别去想！
Don't feel!
看 斯文 天空都醒来了
Look, Sven, the sky is awake.
- 你冷吗？- 有一点
- Are you cold? - A little.
呃… 等等 过来这边
Uh… Wait. Come here.
恩？
Huh?
呜哦
Ooh.
说到我的朋友们 呃…
So, uh, about my friends. Well…
虽然说是「朋友」…
I say "friends"…
他们更像是一个大家庭
they're more like family.
我小的时候 只有斯文陪着我
Anyway, when I was a kid, it was just me and Sven.
直到那群家伙接纳了我们
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
- 他们接纳了你？- 是的
- They did? - Yeah.
我不想吓到你
I don't want to scare you.
他们可能有一点不太一样 还有点吵
They can be a little inappropriate and loud.
是很吵
Very loud.
有时候他们还很顽固
They are also stubborn at times,
还有点傲慢
and a little overbearing.
而且有点重 是非常 非常重
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
不过你会感觉到的 他们都很善良
But you'll get it. They mean well.
克里斯多夫 他们听起来很棒
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
好吧
Okay, then.
来见见我的家人吧
Meet my family.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
那些都是石头
They're rocks.
你越来越靓了啊
You are a sight for sore eyes.
他疯了
He's crazy.
洛克还是老样子 这么有棱角
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
克雷 哇哦… 我都快认不出来你了
Clay, whoa… I don't even recognize you.
你瘦了很多啊
You lost so much weight.
你快点跑 我引开他
I'll distract him while you run.
嗨 斯文的家人！
Hi, Sven's family!
见到你们真高兴
It's nice to meet you.
因为我爱你 安娜 我一定要让你溜掉
Because I love you, Anna, I insist you run.
我知道你们都是爱情专家 哦！
I understand you're love experts. Ooh!
你怎么还不快跑？
Why aren't you running?
呃…
Uh…
好吧 那我先走了
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
- 快走 - 不 不 不 安娜 等一下
- Go. - No, no, no. Anna, wait.
克里斯多夫！
Kristoff!
哇哦！
Whoa!
嘿！
Hey!
克里斯多夫回家了！
Kristoff's home!
- 克里斯多夫在这儿！- 克里斯多夫回来了！
- Kristoff's here! - Kristoff's home!
- 等等 「克里斯多夫」？- 嗯哼
- Wait, "Kristoff"? - Uh-huh.
啊 快让我看看你
Ah, let me look at you.
把你衣服脱了 我帮你洗洗
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
不！不用 我要穿着我的衣服
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
真高兴见到你们
Look, it's great to see you all,
但是外公呢？
but where's Granpabbie?
他在打瞌睡呢
He's napping.
你看你看 我长蘑菇了
But look, I grew a mushroom.
- 我… - 我有火焰水晶了
- I… - I earned my fire crystal.
我取了块肾结石
I passed a kidney stone.
克里斯多夫 抱抱我
Kristoff, pick me up.
你越长越大了
You're getting big.
真棒啊
Good for you.
石精 他们是石精！
Trolls. They're trolls!
他带了个女孩儿回来！
He's brought a girl!
一个女孩儿！
A girl!
- 哇哦！- 这真是个姑娘吗？
- Whoa! - Is that a real girl?
她就像个小杯糕
She's like a little cupcake.
发生了什么？
What's going on?
我已经学会怎么跟着他们疯了
I've learned to just roll with it.
我来看看 明亮的眼睛 挺翘的鼻子
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
强健的牙齿！
strong teeth!
太好了 太好了 她真的很配我们的克里斯多夫
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
等等 等等 哦 不
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
- 不是 - 你们想错了
- No. - You've got the wrong idea.
不 我不是因为这个把她带来的
No. That's not why I brought her here.
是啊 我们不是… 我不是…
Right. We're not… I'm not…
有什么问题吗 亲爱的？
What's the issue, dear?
你为什么要拒绝这么好的男人呢？
Why are you holding back from such a man?
∮ 因为他走路笨笨的？∮
∮ Is it the clumpy way he walks? ∮
- 什么？- ∮ 还是因为他讲话太暴躁？∮
- What? - ∮ Or the grumpy way he talks? ∮
- 哦 不 - ∮ 还是因为他又圆又方 ∮
- Oh, no. - ∮ Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped ∮
∮ 离奇的大脚？∮
∮ Weirdness of his feet? ∮
嘿！
Hey!
∮ 尽管我们知道他洗好了澡 ∮
∮ And though we know he washes well ∮
∮ 但是闻起来还是有点糟 ∮
∮ He always ends up sort of smelly ∮
∮ 但你再也找不到像他这样 ∮
∮ But you'll never meet a fella ∮
∮ 甜蜜又细心的家伙 ∮
∮ Who's as sensitive and sweet ∮
这真的很不错 但是…
That's nice, but…
∮ 他还亟需一点修缮 ∮
∮ So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
- 哇哦 哇哦 哇哦… - ∮ 他还有很多缺点 ∮
- Whoa, whoa, whoa… - ∮ So, he's got a few flaws ∮
∮ 比如他奇怪的头脑 ∮
∮ Like his peculiar brain, dear ∮
∮ 还有他可爱的驯鹿 ∮
∮ His thing with the reindeer ∮
∮ 这都有些超出自然法则 ∮
∮ That's a little outside of nature's laws ∮
问题不是我！
This is not about me!
∮ 他还亟需一点修缮 ∮
∮ So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 但是我们坚信 ∮
∮ But this we're certain of ∮
∮ 你能用一点爱 ∮
∮ You can fix this fixer-upper up ∮
- ∮ 完善这个亟需修缮的家伙 ∮ - 呃…
- ∮ With a little bit of love ∮ - Um…
我们能不能不说这个了？
Can we please just stop talking about this?
我们现在真的有很严重的问题
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
我来帮你解答 告诉我 亲爱的…
I'll say. So, tell me, dear…
∮ 因为他害怕得逃跑？∮
∮ Is it the way that he runs scared? ∮
∮ 还是他缺乏社交方法？∮
∮ Or that he's socially impaired? ∮
∮ 还是他只是想去森林里尿尿？∮
∮ Or that he only likes To tinkle in the woods? ∮
这个我不需要知道
I did not need to know that.
∮ 你隐瞒了你的爱 ∮
∮ Are you holding back your fondness ∮
∮ 因为金发不够男人？∮
∮ Due to his unmanly blondness? ∮
∮ 还是他隐瞒了他最诚实的想法？∮
∮ Or the way he covers up That he's the honest goods? ∮
∮ 他只是亟需一点修缮 ∮
∮ He's just a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 他身上还有一些虫子 ∮
∮ He's got a couple of bugs ∮
- 我没有！- ∮ 他的孤独就是 ∮
- No, I don't! - ∮ His isolation is confirmation ∮
- ∮ 他渴望温暖怀抱的最好证明 ∮ - 哦
- ∮ Of his desperation for healing hugs ∮ - Aw.
∮ 他只是亟需一点修缮 ∮
∮ So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 但我们知道该怎么办 ∮
∮ But we know what to do ∮
∮ 修好这个家伙的最好方法 ∮
∮ The way to fix up this fixer-upper ∮
∮ 就是把你们拴在一起 ∮
∮ Is to fix him up with you ∮
哇哦！
Whoa!
住手 住手 住手！够了！
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
她和别人订婚了 知道吗？
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
∮ 那么 她也需要一点修缮 ∮
∮ So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 那些都是次要的 ∮
∮ That's a minor thing ∮
∮ 她说的「订婚」 还有转变的余地 ∮
∮ Her quote "engagement" Is a flex arrangement ∮
∮ 还有 我没看到戒指 ∮
∮ And by the way, I don't see no ring ∮
∮ 那么 她也需要一点修缮 ∮
∮ So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
- 嘿！哇哦 小心！- ∮ 她正在犹豫不决 ∮
- Hey! Whoa, watch it! - ∮ Her brain's a bit betwixt ∮
∮ 快把未婚夫赶走 ∮
∮ Get the fiance out of the way ∮
∮ 一切就都搞定 ∮
∮ And the whole thing will be fixed ∮
∮ 我们并不是说你能改变他 ∮
∮ We're not saying you can change him ∮
∮ 因为人们都无法改变 ∮
∮ 'Cause people don't really change ∮
∮ 我们的意思是 爱是一种 ∮
∮ We're only saying that love's a force ∮
∮ 强大又陌生的力量 ∮
∮ That's powerful and strange ∮
∮ 当人们愤怒 恐惧 紧张时 ∮
∮ People make bad choices ∮
∮ 难免做了错误的决定 ∮
∮ If they're mad or scared or stressed ∮
∮ 但是散播一点爱吧 ∮
∮ But throw a little love their way ∮
∮ 散播一点爱 ∮
∮ Throw a little love their way ∮
∮ 你会让他们展现最好的一面 ∮
∮ And you'll bring out their best ∮
∮ 真爱会让他们展现最好的一面 ∮
∮ True love brings out the best ∮
∮ 每个人都需要一点修缮 ∮
∮ Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 这就是为什么 ∮
∮ That's what it's all about ∮
- 老爸！- 老姐！
- Father! - Sister!
- ∮ 老哥！∮ - ∮ 我们的成长需要彼此 ∮
- ∮ Brother! ∮ - ∮ We need each other to raise us up ∮
∮ 陪伴在身边 ∮
∮ And round us out ∮
∮ 每个人都需要一点修缮 ∮
∮ Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper ∮
∮ 但是紧要关头 ∮
∮ But when push comes to shove ∮
∮ 那唯一能够 ∮
∮ The only fixer-upper fixer ∮
∮ 修好彼此的修理者就是… ∮
∮ That can fix a fixer-upper is… ∮
∮ 最真 最真 ∮
∮ True, true ∮
∮ 最真的 ∮
∮ True ∮
∮ 爱！∮
∮ Love! ∮
∮ 爱 爱 爱 ∮
∮ Love, love, love ∮
∮ 真爱 真爱 ∮
∮ Love True love ∮
∮ 真爱 ∮
∮ True ∮
安娜 你愿意成为克里斯多夫合法的…
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to be your trollfully wedded…
- 等等 什么？- 你要结婚了
- Wait, what? - You're getting married.
∮ 爱！∮
∮ Love! ∮
安娜？
Anna?
她冷得像冰一样
She's as cold as ice.
这里有陌生的魔法
There is strange magic here.
- 外公 - 过来 把她的手给我
- Granpabbie. - Come, come. Bring her here to me.
安娜 你的生命岌岌可危
Anna, your life is in danger.
你的心里被你姐姐注满了寒冰
There is ice in your heart put there by your sister.
如果不消除掉 那些坚冰将会把你永远的冻结
If not removed, to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
什么？不
What? No.
但是你能消除掉 对吗？
But you can remove it, right?
我无能为力
I cannot.
对不起 克里斯多夫
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
如果坚冰是在她的脑袋里 那就很简单
If it was her head, that would be easy.
但只有真爱的力量可以融化冰冻的心
But only an act of true love can thaw a frozen heart.
真爱的力量？
An act of true love?
可能是真爱之吻？
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
- 事情不太妙 - 你还好吗？
- Something's wrong. - Are you all right?
安娜 我们回去找汉斯
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
汉斯
Hans.
拉我们上去 斯文
Pull us out, Sven.
雪宝 过来！
Olaf, come on!
我来啦！
I'm coming!
我们去吻汉斯咯！
Let's go kiss Hans!
汉斯是谁啊？
Who is this Hans?
我们是来这儿找安娜公主的
We are here to find Princess Anna.
做好防备 但是不要伤到女王
Be on guard, but no harm is to come to the Queen.
都明白吗？
Do you understand?
是的 殿下
Yes, Your Grace.
是女王
The queen.
快 快！快走！
Go, go! Come on!
这里！
There!
在上面！
Up there!
快点！
Come on!
找到她了
We got her.
不 拜托
No. Please.
散开 把箭扔过来
Go around. Toss it.
离我远点！
Stay away!
小心！
Look out!
放箭！放箭！
Fire! Fire!
抓住她！
Get her!
啊！
Ah!
快走！
Come on!
抓住他的胳膊
Grab his arm.
瞄准…
Aim…
这边 这边！
This way, this way!
哇哦！
Whoa!
埃尔莎女王！
Queen Elsa!
不要变成让大家惧怕的怪物
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
哦 不 我到底… 我到底做了什么？
Oh, no. What have… What have I done?
你为什么带我来这？
Why did you bring me here?
我不能让他们把你杀了
I couldn't just let them kill you.
但我会害了艾伦戴尔这座城的 去救安娜
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
安娜还没回来
Anna has not returned.
你就结束这个寒冬吧
If you would just stop the winter.
让夏天回来 拜托了
Bring back summer, please.
你看不出来吗？
Don't you see?
我无能为力
I can't.
你让他们放我走
You have to tell them to let me go.
我会竭尽全力去做
I will do what I can.
坚持住啊
Just hang in there.
快点 再快点！
Come on, buddy, faster!
天啊！
Oh, boy!
哇！我会和你们在城堡里会合！
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
别被人发现了 雪宝
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
我会的！
I will!
- 嗨！- 它是活的！
- Hello! - It's alive!
是安娜公主！
It's Princess Anna!
你没事吧？
Are you gonna be okay?
别担心我了
Don't worry about me.
安娜！
Anna!
- 我们都担心死了 - 殿下
- You had us worried sick. - My Lady.
快给她取暖 快找汉斯王子来
Get her warm. And find Prince Hans, immediately.
我们会的 谢谢
We will. Thank you.
请确保她的安全
Make sure she's safe.
哎 可怜的孩子 看你冻得
Oh, you poor girl, you're freezing.
现在赶紧进屋 暖和暖和
Oh, let's get you inside now and get you warm.
我要出去找安娜公主
I'm going back out to look for Princess Anna.
你不能再冒风险回去了
You cannot risk going out there again.
如果她出事了…
If anything happens to her…
如果公主遭遇不测
If anything happens to the princess,
你不能丢下整个艾伦戴尔不管
you are all Arendelle has left.
他就在里面
He's in here.
汉斯王子
Prince Hans.
安娜
Anna.
你浑身冰凉
You're so cold.
- 汉斯 你快亲我 - 什么？
- Hans, you have to kiss me. - What?
- 现在！就现在！- 等一下
- Now! Now! - Slow down.
我们让你们单独待一会
We'll give you two some privacy.
外面都怎么了？
What happened out there?
埃尔莎用魔法击中了我
Elsa struck me with her powers.
你说过她不会伤害你的
You said she would never hurt you.
我错了
I was wrong.
安娜
Anna.
她施魔法冰封了我的心
She froze my heart,
现在唯一的解救办法就是真爱
and only an act of true love can save me.
真爱之吻
A true love's kiss.
哦 安娜
Oh, Anna.
如果这里有爱你的人就好了
If only there was someone out there who loved you.
什么？
What?
你说过你爱我
You said you did.
我家的王室中我排名十三
As thirteenth in line in my own kingdom,
我根本没有机会继承
I didn't stand a chance.
我明白我必须与其他王室结姻才有机会
I knew I would have to marry into the throne somewhere.
你… 你都在说些什么？
What… what are you talking about?
作为继承人 埃尔莎当然是最合适的人选
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
但可惜她不愿接触任何人
But no one was getting anywhere with her.
- 但你… - 汉斯！
- But you… - Hans!
你那么渴望爱情
You were so desperate for love,
还那么快要和我结婚
you were willing to marry me just like that.
我意识到我们在一起后
I figured after we married,
我得对埃尔莎制造点小意外就更好了
I would have to stage a little accident for Elsa.
汉斯！不 住手
Hans! No. Stop.
但她命中注定如此
But then, she doomed herself,
你还傻兮兮地去追她
and you were dumb enough to go after her.
不要
Please.
现在就剩下把埃尔莎杀了
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
让夏天回来
and bring back summer.
你不是埃尔莎的对手
You're no match for Elsa.
不 你才不是埃尔莎的对手
No, you're no match for Elsa.
而我呢
I, on the other hand,
才是那个拯救艾伦戴尔于危难中的英雄
am the hero who is going to save Arendelle from destruction.
你不会得逞的
You won't get away with this.
哎呀…
Oh…
我已经胜券在握
I already have.
有人吗 救命啊
Please, somebody, help.
救命啊 救命
Please. Please.
天气越来越冷了
It's getting colder by the minute.
如果我们再不抓紧 我们就全都被冻死了
If we don't do something soon, we'll all freeze to death.
汉斯王子
Prince Hans.
安娜公主…
Princess Anna is…
死了
dead.
什么？
What?
她怎么了？
What happened to her?
她是被杀的
She was killed.
是埃尔莎女王干的
By Queen Elsa.
不可能！
No!
那可是她的亲妹妹
Her own sister.
但至少她说完了结婚誓言
At least we got to say our marriage vows.
才死在了我怀里
before she died in my arms.
现在毋庸置疑
There can be no doubt now.
埃尔莎女王就是个魔鬼
Queen Elsa is a monster,
而且我们都陷入了一场严重的威胁
and we are all in grave danger.
汉斯王子
Prince Hans,
艾伦戴尔人民全指望您了
Arendelle looks to you.
带着沉重的心情
With a heavy heart,
我宣布艾伦戴尔女王埃尔莎犯了叛国罪
I charge Queen Elsa of Arendelle with treason.
并判以死刑
And sentence her to death.
快点！
Hurry up!
她现在危险了
She's dangerous.
- 再快点 - 当心
- Move quickly. - Careful.
- 门打不开！- 是被冻上了
- It won't open! - It's frozen shut.
快撞进去！
Put your back into it!
用力！撞！
Come on! Push!
怎么了 兄弟？
What is it, buddy?
你慢点
Hey, watch it.
你到底怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
你不懂你这么跟我说话什么意思
I don't understand you when you talk like that.
停下来！放我下来！
Stop it! Put me down!
不要 斯文！
No, Sven!
我们不会回去的
We're not going back.
她已经跟她的心上人在一起了
She's with her true love.
这是…
What the…
安娜！
Anna!
快！快 斯文
Come on! Come on, boy.
救命啊
Help.
安娜！
Anna!
不
Oh, no.
雪宝？
Olaf?
雪宝 快离开那里
Olaf. Get away from there.
哇！
Wow!
这就是火
So, this is heat.
我超爱
I love it.
不！但别碰火
Ooh! But don't touch it.
汉斯呢？你的真爱之吻不管用吗？
So, where's Hans? What happened to your kiss?
是我错看他了 我们之间不是真爱
I was wrong about him. It wasn't true love.
但我们特地赶回来的
But we ran all the way here.
听我的 雪宝 快离开这里 你会融化的
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here. You'll melt.
我不会离开的
I am not leaving here until.
除非能找到真爱的力量救你
we find some other act of true love to save you.
你有什么好点子吗？
Do you happen to have any ideas?
我都不知道什么叫做爱
I don't even know what love is.
没事 我知道
That's okay, I do.
爱就是
Love is.
把别人看得比自己重要
putting someone else's needs before yours.
就像克里斯多夫把你送回到汉斯身边 然后永远离开了
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you back here to Hans and left you forever.
克里斯多夫爱我？
Kristoff loves me?
哇 你真是对爱一窍不通 对吧？
Wow, you really don't know anything about love, do you?
雪宝 你在融化
Olaf, you're melting.
有的人真的值得为之融化
Some people are worth melting for.
但不应该是这个时候
Just maybe not right this second.
别慌 我来搞定
Don't worry, I've got it.
我们会撑过去… 等一下
We're gonna get through… Oh, wait.
等等 我好像看到什么了
Hang on, I'm getting something.
是克里斯多夫和斯文！
It's Kristoff and Sven!
他们正往回赶
They're coming back this way.
真的… 是他们吗？
They… They are?
哇！他跑得真快啊
Wow! He's really moving fast.
我想我错了
I guess I was wrong.
我想克里斯多夫太爱你了 他不会把你丢下的
I guess Kristoff doesn't love you enough to leave you behind.
快扶我起来 雪宝
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
别 别 别！你要待在火炉边上取暖
No, no, no! You need to stay by the fire and keep warm.
我得去找克里斯多夫
I need to get to Kristoff.
为什么？
Why?
哦 我明白了！
Oh, I know why!
那就是你的真爱力量！
There's your act of true love right there!
跨越海湾的那个劲头 活脱脱一个勇敢但有汗臭味的驯鹿国王！
Riding across the fjords like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
快点！
Come on!
小心！
Look out!
哦！
Oh!
呃… 往回走
Uh… Back this way.
我们被困了
We're trapped.
啊…
Oh…
哇！
Whoa!
从这滑下去 安娜！
Slide, Anna!
我们成功了！
We made it!
快 快 快！
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
快点 哥们 再快点
Come on, buddy, faster.
克里斯多夫！
Kristoff!
坚持住！
Keep going!
克里斯多夫！
Kristoff!
快！
Come on!
不
No.
哇！
Whoa!
斯文… 斯文！
Sven… Sven!
好样的
Good boy.
克里斯多夫
Kristoff.
- 克里斯多夫… - 安娜…
- Kristoff… - Anna…
安娜！
Anna!
埃尔莎！别再逃避了！
Elsa! You can't run from this!
你好好照顾我妹妹
Just take care of my sister.
你妹妹？
Your sister?
她从山上回来的时候又虚又冷
She returned from the mountain weak and cold.
她说你冰封了她的心
She said that you froze her heart.
不
No.
我想救她 可都来不及了
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
她冷得像块冰 头发全白了
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
你妹妹死了
Your sister is dead.
都是你的错
Because of you.
不
No.
克里斯多夫
Kristoff.
安娜！
Anna!
埃尔莎？
Elsa?
不要！
No!
安娜！
Anna!
天啊 安娜！
Oh. Anna!
不 不！
No, no!
不要
Please, no.
安娜？
Anna?
哦 埃尔莎
Oh, Elsa.
你为救我牺牲了你自己？
You sacrificed yourself for me?
我爱你
I love you.
「真爱的力量可以融化冰冻的心」
"An act of true love will thaw a frozen heart."
「爱能融化一切」
"Love will thaw."
就是爱 对啊
Love. Of course.
埃尔莎？
Elsa?
可以用爱！
Love!
我就知道你能做到
I knew you could do it.
这是我一生中最美好的时光
Hands down, this is the best day of my life.
也很可能是最后的时光
And, quite possibly, the last.
雪宝！坚持住 小家伙
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
哇 哇 哇！
Oh, oh, oh!
我的小云朵！
My own personal flurry!
别… 别… 别
Uh… uh… uh… uh.
安娜？
Anna?
可她冰封了你的心
But she froze your heart.
我看这里心被冻上的是你
The only frozen heart around here is yours.
太棒了！
Wonderful!
设定航路 先生
Setting course, sir.
我会把这家伙送回他的国家
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
我们就看看他那十二个哥哥怎么处理他
We shall see what his 12 big brothers think of his behavior.
艾伦戴尔感谢您 大人
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
我不能接受
This is unacceptable.
我是个可怜的受害者 我精神上受了打击
I am a victim of fear. I've been traumatized.
啊！我的脖子扭了
Ah! My neck hurts.
船上有看病的医生吗？
Is there a doctor that I could see?
我要求见女王！
And I demand to see the queen!
女王下达了命令
Oh. I have a message from the queen.
「艾伦戴尔从今日起
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever.
将不与黄鼠狼镇进行任何邦交「
no longer do business of any sort with Weaseltown."
「威尔镇」
"Weselton."
- 是威尔镇！- 快走
- It's Weselton! - Let's go.
快点 快点！
Come on, come on, come on!
好 我在走
Okay, okay, here I come.
- 杆子！啊！- 对不起啦
- Pole! Whoops! - Sorry.
好 好
Okay, okay.
我们到了 哦！
Here we are. Oh!
我欠你个雪橇
I owe you a sled.
- 你认真的吗？- 对啊！
- Are you serious? - Yes!
这可是最新的款式
And it's the latest model.
不行 我不能要
No, I can't accept this.
你必须要 不能退 不能换 女王的旨意
You have to. No returns. No exchanges. Queen's orders.
她封你为艾伦戴尔法定运冰官
She's named you the Official Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
- 什么？就没听过这个名字 - 有这个名字
- What? That's not a thing. - Oh, sure it is.
这上面还有个杯架 你喜欢吗？
And it even has a cup holder. Do you like it?
喜欢？简直太爱了！
Like it? I love it!
哇
Whoa.
我真想亲你！
I could kiss you!
我可以 我是说 我希望 我…
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd…
我能吗？我是说 我们可以吗？
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
等一下 什么？
Wait, what?
可以
We may.
嗯
Mmm.
夏天！
Summer!
哇…
Ooh…
嗨
Hello.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
是冰！
Ice!
哦！哇哇…
Ooh! Whoo-hoo…
旋转着滑
Swing me.
哦…
Ooh…
我喜欢开放城堡大门
I like the open gates.
我们不会再关上了
We are never closing them again.
埃尔莎 这冰鞋是好看 可我不会滑
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful, but you know I don't skate.
来吧！你可以的！
Come on! You can do it!
小心 驯鹿过来啦
Look out. Reindeer coming through.
我抓住了 我抓住了 我不行了 不行了
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
嗨 小伙伴们！
Hey, guys!
就是这样 雪宝
That's it, Olaf.
滑起来 转圈圈 滑起来 转圈圈
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.
滑起来
Go.
哇！
Oh!